Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
You may be seated, thank you.
I want to believe we are here to sow to the Spirit.
Amen!
I cannot hear you.
Each time we listen to the Word of God, there is a passage there that I love so much.
“You are already cleansed because of the Word which I have spoken to you.” John 15:3
After listening to the Word of God, can we say, "You are free"?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you are still living in the past, you are taking journeys to yesterday.
The Word of God helps us to stop reliving the past in our present life.
Tell your neighbour, “The Word of God helps us to stop reliving...”
You know what I mean by reliving - the past in our present life.
When you receive the Word of God, the past will no longer control your thinking pattern.
That is when you know you are already free.
When you receive the Word of God, the past will no longer control your thinking pattern
or your behaviours.
"Yes. How will I pay my school fees? How will I pay my house rent? I'm sick. Somebody sick is in the hospital.
What is going to happen? How will I get...? I don't know whether I will be paid my salary.
I don't know what will happen here."
When you receive the Word of God, the past will no longer control your thinking pattern.
I mean, your behaviours.
Wherever you are coming from, whatever you have gone through
before coming here does not matter.
This is what the Bible means by,
“You are already cleansed because of the Word I have spoken to you”.
Are you with me?
Tell your neighbour,
“When you receive the Word of God, the past will no longer control your thinking pattern.”
I mean, your behaviours.
You know, before you came here today, you were so worried, you were thinking how to do this or that,
"How will I do it? How will I go about it?",
but after receiving the Word of God you start laughing.
The pain may be there but yet, the joy has overcome over the shadow.
You can have the pain and at the same time be happy.
Tell your neighbour, “You can have the pain and at the same time be happy”
because the part that has pain is not yours; it’s not part of you.
The part that has that pain is not part of you; it’s a shade.
A cover - you know the snake; snake enters the shade.
The Lord never consults your past to determine your future.
He never says, "Oh!"
If your past was consulted, you would not be here today.
A lot of things is out there to stop you from coming.
When you receive that Word...
The Word has been delivered - we don't know whether you have received the Word.
Some receive with their ears and some receive with their heart.
If you have received the Word of God, the past will no longer control your thinking pattern.
The way you think, the manner you think...
I will bind your feet to the path of righteousness today.
Rise up; let's start that one first, because what I'm saying looks strange to you,
"What does this man saying? He says I should not think of where I'm coming from?
I should not think about my debts?"
That is the position of faith.
Faith is expecting Jesus to do what He promised.
Right now, begin to bind your feet to the path of righteousness; prayer.
Bind your feet right now to the path of righteousness because you are made righteous.
You are the righteousness of God in Christ Jesus.
Begin to bind your feet to the path of righteousness.
In the mighty name of Jesus Christ.
Amen!
- I bind you to the work of the Cross.
- Amen.
I cannot hear you.
Amen!
Yes; you are the righteousness of God in Christ Jesus.
Open your lips and confess this.
Believe you are bound to the path of righteousness.
Yes.
You can say, "No", and say "Yes" with an independent mind, that can think, reason...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Be bound to the work of the Cross, in the name of Jesus!
Amen!
Be bound to the work of the Cross, in the mighty name of Jesus!
With His mercy, forgiveness and love,
be bound to the work of the Cross, in the name of Jesus!
Amen!
Thank You, Lord.
You may be seated.
Hallelujah.
Now, you will begin to think differently.
Begin right now.
Now you are free, look forward to those things that lie ahead.
You are to get yourself ready.
If you have not positioned yourself, God cannot position you.
Do you listen to me?
You are to first position yourself for God to position you.
If you just say, "I'm not interested in what they are talking about", then you have not positioned yourself.
You are to position yourself for God to position you.
Believe God is not a man; when He says yes, yes is yes.
You need to know the power you are under right now.
You ask yourself, "What power am I under? Am I under man? Am I under T.B. Joshua? Am I under Jesus Christ?"
You need to know the power you are under.
The songs says,
Leave it for God
Don’t worry yourself
Don’t cry no more
Jesus is alive
Praise God
You can face tomorrow
He understands
What you are passing through today
Let God glorify His name
You listen to that?
I know this is just a mere song; you sing it every day, "Leave if for God..."
What are you leaving for God?
Your worries, your care.
Are you actually leaving your worries for God?
We see our faith as a hobby, a game.
You know; games - we are not serious about games; when it does not go well, we look for another game.
It is not a hobby; there is no alternative.
Faith is faith.
You need to know the difference between your faith and a hobby.
It is not a hobby, it is not a game that we try and leave.
No, you can try; you have no alternative.
You have to be visible and clear.
If you are not visible and clear, there is no light.
You have to position yourself for God to position you.
Where everything is visible and clear, there is light.
How do we position ourselves?
You must know the power you are under.
You must be here by revelation.
Not by advice; somebody advised you to come here...
I think you have to be here by revelation.
Somebody advised you to come here, or you follow a friend here, or you are looking for your boss;
your boss is a member of this church, you want to go there, so you use that opportunity to see your boss,
or your friends.
Your foundation must be revelation.
God sent His Word to heal His people and His people are products of revelation.
If you are here not by revelation, you will be just looking at what is happening here,
"Oh my God, it happened; but it has not happened to me."
Does it need to happen to you before you believe?
I think that when it happens to someone and you are looking how it happened,
that will give you a grace to receive a "mother of miracles".
Yes.
That prepares our faith.
That makes us stronger.
You have to be tired of reliving the past in your present life.
Tell your neighbour, “Be tired of reliving the past in your present life.”
I cannot hear you.
"Be tired of reliving the past in your present life.”
You continue to think of what happened to you yesterday;
you were disappointed yesterday and you believe that today you also must be disappointed.
Anywhere you go you continue to think about yesterday's disappointment.
The way somebody, your husband behaved yesterday; you wake up this morning having that attitude -
you walk towards your husband, "Good morning", believing that he will behave the same way - no!
Once you are a Christian, the past will no longer control your thinking pattern.
Once you are a Christian and you are delivered, the past will no longer control your thinking pattern.
I mean, it will no longer control your attitude.
"I know many things happened to me yesterday - but it was yesterday."
History; the fact that we didn't make it yesterday makes you believe that you will not make it at all -
this is the life we live.
Those processes, thoughts, attitude; an encounter you had yesterday you carry along to process it today.
It can't work.
I bind your feet to the path of righteousness, in the name of Jesus!
Amen!
Righteousness exalts
and you are that righteousness of God.
Jesus has made you righteous.
I bind your feet to the righteousness of God, in Jesus Christ’s name!
Amen!
I bind your feet to the righteousness of God!
In Jesus Christ’s name!
Amen!
Let me see your faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You believe all things pass away, right now?
Yes!
You have to be strong; be ready.
I am just preparing you for the blessing you are about to receive.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You should be talking about maintenance, not blessing.
Don't talk about blessing; you are blessed already.
Blessing is a past tense victory; it is a past tense issue.
Amen!
What you are waiting for - blessing - is a past tense issue.
What you should be talking about is maintenance.
Everything you have been given; there is nothing you are able to maintain - even your children.
Some of your children today have become enemies; they can insult or embarrass you.
When you see them you are afraid even to look at their faces, because of the upbringing.
Many of you cannot even maintain children God had given to you.
If you give birth to a child, and you can not maintain it, you cannot train it- what else can you teach them?
There is nothing you can teach, if you cannot teach your children.
Baby, you have a birth to...
Right from an embryo... and suddenly he or she becomes big and now can say,
"- Please! Don't talk to me like that!
- I'm sorry." That is your baby.
This is life.
We are embarrassing ourselves and we think we are embarrassing God.
Each time you are looking for blessing, "God, bless me!..." - what about the one He has given you?
Even your little one, baby?
God rejoices and is happy concerning the way we maintain the blessing given to us.
How you maintain your blessing will determine how it will increase.
When you think about many blessings God has given to you, and how you maintained them,
you will likely not even want to ask God for any blessing, because the one given to you you didn't maintain.
And you keep asking for more, more, more...
We are not ashamed.
Think about maintenance.
Think about what?
Maintenance.
Don’t let the blessing of God control your direction;
let God who gave you blessing be the Controller.
Today, it is the blessing God had given to us that is controlling us.
When money comes, you think it will tell you where to live, what to wear, how to do, how to go to church,
whether to go to church or not, where to go to church, which kind of church you should go to,
because of money you have,
instead of God, who gave you the blessing, to be the Controller.
This is the maintenance we are talking about.
"I need healing..." - what about the healing you had in the past?
"I need money, breakthrough, position..."
Before, you could have spent five hours in the church; now, you have a big position,
you became director, MD of the company, you cannot spend two minutes in the church any more.
When you are going to church, you carry your newspaper along with you, as if it was the Bible.
These are the things God takes into consideration.
When God looks at all this, He begins to look at this blessing - we are blessed to bless others,
but today what has happened?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Think about what?
Maintenance.
Tell your neighbour, "Think about maintenance".
I cannot hear you.
Think about maintenance.
Even our relationship with a husband or wife; we cannot maintain them.
Whole thing falls apart.
We fail to understand that the husband and wife - when God brings them together for the purpose of,
"where she is strong he is weak, and where she is weak he is strong" - that is the meaning of marriage.
So, we can counsel ourselves.
TT Robert Begier 22/06/2018
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 30/06/2018